((リン：カカシ…))
（カカシ）落ちない。
Kakashi…
It won't wash off!
Kakashi: Shadow of the ANBU Black Ops
A Mask that Hides the Heart
（シカク）火影様よりの書状
受け取るがいい。
Accept this from the Hokage!
Deliver it to Lord Tsuchikage
土影様に届けよ
至急　ご返答願いたいとな。
and relay to him that we desire
an immediate response!
There's no need to deliver
anything to him.
届けるまでもない
ここで返答してやる。
We'll give you your answer
right here!
慌てぬほうがよいときもある。
Sometimes it's best not
to be so hasty.
なに！？
What?!
四代目風影！
The Fourth Kazekage?
Why is the Hidden Sand here?
なぜ　砂隠れが。
ここは　我ら砂隠れの
国境でもある。
This is Hidden Sand territory.
It would be unwise to have
an incident occur here.
ここで騒ぎを起こされては困る。
We'll put out any sparks
that rain down over us.
降りかかる火の粉は
振り払わねばなるまい。
砂は砂として動く。
The Sand will move accordingly,
as the Sand.
Remember that,
whatever you decide to do.
それを承知で
行動してもらいたい。
Scatter!
散！
平和条約締結の申し込み
どうなさるおつもりです？
What about the request to enter into
the peace treaty?
Naturally, it will be turned down.
当然　お断りなさるんでしょうな。
Whatever the Hidden Leaf negotiates
with the Hidden Sand,
いかに木ノ葉隠れが
砂隠れと組もうが→
我らの　一枚岩の結束に
敵うものはありません。
nothing will challenge
the unity of the Stone.
– Right!
– Exactly!
そのとおりです。
（オオノキ）静まれぃ！
Silence!
もちろん　岩隠れの結束は
わしの誇りじゃぜ。
Naturally, I am proud of
the unity of the Stone.
しかし　岩隠れの命運をかけ→
However…
With the pride on our line,
we sent 1000 of our shinobi.
一千余名の忍を投入した
侵攻作戦を→
頓挫させたのは→
And I hear that it took just one of them,
the Yellow Flash, to stop the invasion.
黄色い閃光
ただ１人だったと聞く。
それもまた事実じゃぜ。
And that's the reality of it.
（ライドウ）今度　岩隠れと平和条約が
締結されるんだってさ。
I hear they're going to enter
into a peace treaty
with the Hidden Stone.
（ゲンマ）紙切れ一枚に
どんだけ効力があるか。
How much faith can we put
in a single piece of paper?
（ガイ）うむ…　それは言える。
That's for sure.
You guys, think about
the burden on Lord Third!
お前たちも
三代目様の苦労も考えろって。
In any case, the long, great war
will be over for now.
（アスマ）とにかく長かった大戦も
ひとまず　これで終わりだ。
Let's toast with some dumplings!
（紅）おだんごで乾杯しましょう。
（ガイ）お～い　カカシ！
Hey, Kakashi!
Want to join us for some dumplings?
こっち来て　だんご食わないか？
最近　つきあい悪いな　アイツ。
He's not too sociable these days.
悩みでもあるのか？
Is something bothering him?
そりゃ　手放しで　はしゃげる
心境じゃないだろ。
Well, you can't expect him
to be jumping for joy.
やっぱり　オビトとリンのことが…。
Are you talking about
Obito and Rin?
あぁ　心に大きな傷が残るさ。
Yeah.
That would definitely leave
a hole in your heart…
((カカシ…))
Kakashi…
リン…。
Rin…
HOW A SHINOBI SHOULD DIE
（ホムラ）ご苦労じゃった。
Well done!
（コハル）ひとまず胸を
なでおろしたわい。
We can breathe
a sigh of relief for a while.
（ダンゾウ）こんな条約で満足ですか？
Are you satisfied with
an agreement like this?
岩隠れの活動を認め→
To forgive
the Hidden Stone's actions
賠償請求権を放棄するとは…。
and drop our demands
for compensation…
戦争に負けたも同然の内容。
It's as though we lost the war!
ヒルゼンは　どう思うか？
What do you think, Hiruzen?
（ヒルゼン）これ以上の戦争の継続は→
Continuing the war
any further would be disastrous
疲弊しきった木ノ葉にとっても
致命的。
for the already
exhausted Hidden Leaf.
同意を導き出すための譲歩…。
It's a step toward finding
common ground…
このたびの大戦で→
Many of my friends gave
their lives for this great war!
多くの盟友たちが
犠牲になっておる！
彼らを犬死にさせたも同然だ。
It's like they died in vain!
その責任は
すべて火影である　わしにある。
And I assume full responsibility
for that.
どう責任をとるつもりだ？
How will you take responsibility?
三代目火影の座を辞し→
I intend to step down as the Third Hokage,
and have the Fourth Hokage installed.
四代目に譲るつもりじゃ。
残念だのう。
How regrettable…
三代目は　よくやっておったが。
The Third Hokage was
doing a fine job…
Hmm…
元を正せば
三代目が甘い考えゆえ→
Truth be told, the Third Hokage
was too soft…
あそこまで
里が追い込まれたのだ。
and he allowed the village
to be pushed into a corner.
今　必要とされる火影とは
里に変革を成し→
We need a Hokage
who will change things,
忍に掟を徹底させる。
そんな人材だ。
and enforce the laws of the shinobi.
We need someone like that.
ほう　適当な者はおるのかえ？
And? Is there such a person?
わしは　伝説の三忍と謳われる→
I recommend Orochimaru,
one of the Legendary Sannin.
大蛇丸を推薦する。
– Oh…
– Him?
三代目は　どう思うのだ？
What do you think, Lord Third?
大蛇丸は
戦乱の時代にあってこそ→
Orochimaru is truly a genius
in this age of war.
才能に満ち溢れる天才
と言えましょう。
しかし　その瞳の奥には→
However…
A sinister will and greed lurk
deep behind those eyes.
悪意と野望が潜んでおります。
そのような素養を持つ者に→
Such a person cannot be given
the duties of a Hokage.
火影は任せられませぬ。
三代目！
Lord Third!
波風ミナトを推薦いたします。
I recommend Minato Namikaze.
自来也の弟子筋にあたる男。
A pupil of Jiraiya…
つまり　三代目の孫弟子じゃ。
In other words,
a disciple of your disciple.
黄色い閃光と異名をとる手練。
A man so skilled,
he's nicknamed the Yellow Flash.
ほう。
Oh!
ミナトは　まだ若い！
Minato is still too young.
神無毘橋に勝利し→
He emerged victorious
at the Battle of Kannabi Bridge,
第三次忍界大戦
終結に導いた功績は大。
and distinguished himself
by leading the way to end
of the Third Great Shinobi War.
わしは反対だ。
I am opposed!
他の皆は　どうじゃえ？
What about the rest of you?
お前は　火の意志を
継ぐ者と思っておる。
I believe that you will carry on
the Will of Fire.
そんなお前に　これからの木ノ葉を
そして　忍世界の未来を託す。
So I want to entrust you with
the future of the Hidden Leaf…
and the shinobi world.
受けてくれるな？
You will accept, won't you?
（ミナト）三代目の信頼に
お応えできるように。
I shall do my best to deserve
your trust, Lord Third.
本来なら　もっと
よい環境を整えたうえで→
I wish I could have passed this on
under better circumstances…
引き継げたらと
思っていたのだが→
目の前に広がるのは
平穏な未来ではない。
What lies ahead is not peaceful.
覚悟はできています。
I'm prepared for it.
うむ。
Good.
お前なら　やってくれるじゃろ。
I know you can do it.
そんなとこで　どうしたってばね？
What are you doing there?
三代目様からのお呼び出しは→
What did Lord Third want with you?
何だったの？
ああ…。
Well…
何か　お小言をもらったのね。
Did you get scolded?
平気　平気！　そんなの→
So what?
Don't worry about it, ya know!
気にすることないってばね！
いや　そうじゃなくて。
Well, it wasn't that…
じゃあ　何だってばね？
Then what?
あの…　四代目の火影をやれと。
Well…
He wants me to be
the Fourth Hokage.
そうだってばね。
Oh really?
Don't mind the Hokage—
火影なんか　気にすることない…。
What?! What did you just say?
今　何て言ったってばね！？
四代目火影を仰せつかった。
I've been named the Fourth Hokage.
おめでとうだってばね！
Congratulations, ya know!
おいおい！
Hey, hey…
お役目　ご苦労さまです！
Thank you very much for
all your hard work.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
ヒルゼンの思惑どおりの
流れになってしまった。
It's all going Hiruzen's way.
（大蛇丸）三代目の本心は
ミナトを傀儡とし→
The Third Hokage intends to
use Minato as a puppet
師弟で木ノ葉を牛耳ることね。
and keep ruling the Hidden Leaf.
このままのやり方では
木ノ葉に未来はない。
At this rate, the Hidden Leaf
has no future.
まだ諦めることはありません。
Don't give up yet.
この研究が成功すれば→
If my research is successful,
木ノ葉隠れの権力を
掌握するなど　たやすいこと。
it will be easy to grasp
the power of the Hidden Leaf.
フン…。
権力を握るためなら
多少　強引な手段を使う用意も。
To grasp power…
stronger measures must be prepared.
時が来れば手段は選ばぬ。
When the time comes,
we won't be choosing measures.
しかし　今はまだ　その時ではない。
But, it's not time yet.
だいたい　あやつに人望があれば
もう少し　なんとか…。
Generally, if he's popular at all,
he should…
行くぞ　甲！　乙！　丙！
Let's go, Kinoe, Kinoto, Hinoe!
（３人）はっ！
– Sir!
I, HIRUZEN SARUTOBI, HEREBY ANNOUNCE
MY RESIGNATION AS HOKAGE, AND APPOINT
MINATO NAMIKAZE AS THE FOURTH HOKAGE.
SIGNED, THIRD HOKAGE HIRUZEN SARUTOBI
な…　なんと！？
What's going on?!
（ガイ）お～い　カカシ！
Hey, Kakashi!
「いかに死すべきか」！？
なんだ　これ…。
"How a Shinobi Should Die"?!
What is this?
返してくれ！
Give it back.
何ごとだ？
あっ　そうだった！
What's going on?
Oh yeah!
今　四代目火影が発表された！
The Fourth Hokage
was just announced!
びっくりすんなよ？
Don't be shocked!
四代目火影は　ミナト先生だ！
Minato Sensei will be
the Fourth Hokage!
RIN NOHARA
リン…。
Rin…
ミナト先生が火影になるそうだよ。
It seems like Minato Sensei
is going to be Hokage!
先生なら
プロフェッサーの後継者となり→
Minato Sensei will be
the Professor's successor
木ノ葉隠れの里を…。
and change the Hidden Leaf…
and the shinobi world.
忍の世界を変えてくれる。
もう　お前たちのような
犠牲を出すことは…。
There won't be any more sacrifices
like you guys…
頼むぞ　四代目。
I'm counting on you…
Fourth Hokage.
一命にかえても。
I shall dedicate my life to it.
((カカシ　さっきのあの術は
もう使わないほうがいい。
Kakashi. You shouldn't use
that jutsu anymore.
見たところ　一点集中型の突き。
From what I could see,
your focused concentrated attack
undoubtedly has power and speed…
確かに破壊力とスピードはあるけど→
But it makes you move too fast
自分自身の移動スピードが速すぎて→
相手のカウンターを
見切ることができない→
to be able to ascertain
your opponent's counterattack.
It's still an imperfect jutsu.
(不完全な術だからね))
Those were Minato Sensei's words
back then…
《あのとき　ミナト先生は
ああおっしゃったが…》
Obito…
《オビト…》
((オビト：この　俺の写輪眼を
やるからよ。
I'm giving you…my Sharingan.
Whatever the village may say…
you are…a great jonin.
里のヤツらが何て言おうと
お前は立派な上忍だ。
それが　俺の気持だ。
That's how I really feel…
So please accept it.
(受け取ってくれ))
《お前にもらった
この左目の写輪眼。
You gave me this Sharingan
in my left eye…
千鳥と写輪眼が一つになったとき
この術は完全になった。
When Chidori and Sharingan became one,
it became a complete jutsu.
しかし　その術でリンの命を…》
But…that jutsu took Rin's life.
千鳥！
Chidori!
So this is where you've been!
こんなところにいたのか。
任務だから　すぐ出頭しろって。
You have a mission.
You've been summoned immediately.
Enter.
どうぞ。
任務ですか？
There's a mission?
ああ。　平和条約に関する書類を
受け取ってきてもらいたい。
Yes, I want you to retrieve the documents
relating to the peace treaty.
はい。
Yes.
There are still some shinobi
who desire war.
忍の中には
まだ戦乱の世を望む勢力もいる。
その者たちが書類を奪い→
And there are rumors that they are trying
to steal the documents to create discord.
仲違いさせようとしている
という情報がある。
心して任務にかかってくれ。
Please do your best on this mission.
はい。
Yes, sir.
I'll wrap this up!
《一気に　かたをつける！　千鳥》
Chidori!
Kakashi…
((リン：カカシ…。
カカシ　カカシ。
Kakashi…
(カカシ！))
Kakashi!
死ね！
Die!
Severe Leaf Hurricanes!
（ガイ）木ノ葉　剛力旋風！
クッ！　新手か？
Another one?
お前らしくもない！
何をぼやっとしている！
This isn't like you!
Why are you spaced out?
す　すまん…。
S-Sorry…
カカシ？
Kakashi?
しっかりしろ！
Get a hold of yourself!
そうか…。
はい。
I see…
Yes…
あんなカカシは
見たことがありません。
I've never seen Kakashi like that.
密かに同行してもらって
よかったよ。
I'm glad I secretly sent you.
こんなときこそ
永遠のライバルとしては→
To help him at a time like this…
That's what an eternal rival is for!
何かしてやらないと！
とは思うのですが！
That's what I believe, but…
もう十分やってくれた。
You've already done a lot.
あとは任せてもらえるかな。
Will you leave the rest to me?
HIDDEN LEAF HOSPITAL
ん？
ミナト先生！
Minato Sensei! I mean…Lord Fourth…
いや　四代目！
今までどおりの呼び名でいいよ。
Address me as you always have.
だいたい
俺がふさわしい人材なのか→
Some in the village think I'm not qualified
for the position and oppose me.
里の中でも
反対の立場の者もいるしね。
今日　ここに来たのは→
I came here today…
キミに　火影直属の
暗部への配属を命じるためだ。
to assign you to the ANBU
under my direct control.
Why me?
なぜ俺なんかを…。
右腕となって働いてもらいたい。
I want you to be my right-hand man…
AN
HOW A SHINOBI SHOULD DIE
EQUIPMENT DEPT.
あなたの装備一式です。
Here's a set of gear for you.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
I want you to leave your current mission
and take on a special mission.
＜旬の野菜が大好きな豆助＞
Was there an issue?
It's nothing like that.
This is confidential, but...
豆助
Kushina's pregnant!
きょうのお野菜は
今が旬のあれよ？
Congratulations!
Thank you. That's why…
＜　その野菜とは？＞
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"Minato's Death."
…I want you to be Kushina's bodyguard.
＜　それは…＞
MINATO'S DEATH
Tune i